Victor Klymko, Ph.D.

Pastoor Petersstraat 69, Eindhoven, Netherlands +31(0)614417196 • vklymko@yahoo.com

PHYSICIST / ELECTRICAL ENGINEER

Integrating thorough physics insight into efficient engineering solutions. Modeling and testing of innovations in smart lighting and sustainable energy components. Delivering results and managing collaborations for multipartner European projects. Engineering and technical expertise includes

Solutions: Piezoelectric transformers; half-bridge converters

Design: Vibration and acoustic piezoelectric energy harvesters

Methodologies: Experimental, Analytical, Finite Element Analysis (FEA), Method of Moments

Hardware: Network / impedance analyzers, generators, multimeters, o-scopes

Tools: Matlab, COMSOL, PZFlex, Mathematica, SPICE, Mathcad, Maple, HFSS

Programming: FORTRAN, C++, HTML

OS's: Windows ('98, XP, 7), MacOS X, Linux (Ubuntu), Unix (Solaris)

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Eindhoven University of Technology (<u>TU/e</u>), Netherlands

Postdoctoral Researcher 01/2012 - Present

Energy efficient and intelligent lighting systems (partners: Osram, Philips, NXP Semiconductors,...)

Analytical and numerical modeling of piezoelectric transformers (PT) for powering LED lighting systems. Using signal processing to increase the power delivered by PT. Integration of PT into a switched capacitor converter to realize a smart LED dimming solution.

- Developed analytical model for a multilayer PT including PCB mounting losses.
- Preserved the waveform and spectrum of a square pulse signal while maintaining high efficiency.
- Successfully tested the theory on a self-built half-bridge converter loaded with PT.

SMArt systems Co-design (partners: Philips, ON Semiconductor, ST Microelectronics,...)

Design, analytical and numerical modeling of vibration energy harvesters. FEA modeling of ultrasonic transducers and the surrounding media. Calculation, measurement of the ultrasonic energy harvesting efficiency.

- Designed and modeled an ultrasonic energy harvesting system for use in MRI machines.
- Tested a transducer array to focus the ultrasonic energy on the harvester.
- Introduced a phased array to set the position of the sound pressure peak at the harvester's location.
- Contributed to the project web site development

Taught the "Sustainable power sources for smart buildings" workshop.

University of Mississippi (OleMiss), MS, USA

Visiting Assistant Professor

07/2010 - 12/2011

Lectured general physics and physics for science and engineering 200-level courses. Supervised graduate teaching assistants and graders. Advised a graduate student on a research project. Wrote 2 research proposals.

Visiting Instructor 07/2009 - 06/2010

Taught physics lectures and laboratories for up to 70 pre-medical or engineering students.

Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Mississippi, USA

Graduate Research Assistant

08/2004 - 05/2009

Studied Lamb waves in multidomain ferroelectric plates. Developed a FORTRAN FEA code to calculate displacement components and surface charge induced by an ultrasonic wave in the periodically poled LiNbO₃ wafer. Calculated analytically and numerically the dispersion curves and piezoelectric coupling for multidomain ZX-cut LiNbO₃, confirmed the calculations with experimental data. Designed and tested a new efficient ultrasonic delay line. Obtained two \$2500 grants from the UM Graduate School to fund the research.

Page Two

Department of Electrical Engineering, University of Mississippi, USA

Graduate Research Assistant

08/2002 - 07/2004

Derived Electric Dyadic Green's function for hard surface power combiner with alternating metallic and dielectric strips. Calculated electromagnetic fields inside hard surface waveguides due to a current probe, a current dipole, and the closed and unclosed current rings using Method of Moments implemented in FORTRAN and Matlab codes. Prepared regular progress reports.

EDUCATION

PhD, Physics, Solid State Physics, 2009

University of Mississippi, University, MS, USA

MS, Electrical Engineering, Electromagnetics, 2004

University of Mississippi, University, MS, USA

MS, Radio Physics and Electronics, Theoretical Radiophysics, 1996

Kharkiv National University, Kharkiv, Ukraine

SELECTED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- V. Klymko, M.A.M. Hendrix, J.L. Duarte, and E. Lomonova, "Efficient waveform preservation of discrete spectrum signals with multilayered piezoelectric transformer," accepted.
- V. Ostrovskii, A. B. Nadtochiy, V. A. Klymko, "Velocity dispersion of plate acoustic waves in a multidomain phononic superlattice," Phys. Rev. B, 82(1), 014302 (2010).
- V. Ostrovskii, V. A. Klymko, A. B. Nadtochiy, "Plate wave stop bands in a periodically poled lithium niobate," JASA-EL, 125(4), EL129 (2009).
- V. A. Klymko, A. B. Nadtochiy and I. V. Ostrovskii, "Theoretical and experimental study of plate acoustic waves in ZX-cut lithium niobate," IEEE Trans. UFFC, 55(12), 2726 (2008).
- V. A. Klymko, A. B. Yakovlev, I. A. Eshrah, A. A. Kishk and A. W. Glisson, "Dyadic Green's function of an ideal hard surface circular waveguide with application to excitation and scattering problems," Radio Science, 40, RS3014 (2004).

SELECTED CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

- V. Klymko, M. Roes, J. van Duivenbode, and E. Lomonova, "Phased transducer array for ultrasonic energy harvesting inside an MRI machine," Proc. Joint IEEE UFFC-IUS Symposia (2013).
- V. A. Klymko, I. V. Ostrovskii, D. Sedorook, "Aperiodic multidomain ferroelectric transducers," Fundamental Physics of Ferroelectrics Symp. (2010).
- V. A. Klymko, I. V. Ostrovskii, "Phononic band gaps in periodically corrugated lithium niobate plate," 156-th meeting Acoust. Soc. Am. (2008).
- V. A. Klymko, A. B. Yakovlev, A. A. Kishk, A. W. Glisson, "Scattering by closed and unclosed metallic rings in a circular waveguide," ACES, 94-101 (2006).
- V. A. Klymko, A. B. Yakovlev, I. A. Eshrah, A. A. Kishk, A. W. Glisson, "Scattering by open metal obstacles in a circular waveguide: dyadic Green's function approach," IEEE-AP Int. Symp., 2, 2127 (2004).